Ajeetkumar Vishwakarma

Senior Software Engineer

Contact: ajeet.innovation@gmail.com I +91 9967485884

Location: Mumbai, MH, India

Profile: LinkedIn

Summary _____

Software engineer with 7.8 years of experience developing robust code for high volume businesses. Team player engineer with can-do attitude and strong user focus.

Tools and Technologies ____

Programming Languages Java 8 and 11, Oracle SQL, Python, Linux Shell

Frameworks Spring boot Microservices, REST Platforms AWS, S3, ECS, Redis, Docker

Testing & Deployment Junit & Mockito, SonarQube, Jenkins, GitLab

Version control & build Tools Git and SVN, Maven

Familiar technologies JSP/Servlets, JSON, XML, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

Work Experience _____

HERE Technologies, SSE

Jun 2021 – Ongoing

Projects: Microservices - Validation, Repairs, and Context Loaders

Contributions:

- 1. Developed the features supporting validations and repairs
- 2. Improved request tracking using AWS S3
- 3. Improved Code quality, Testing and coverage from 10% to 75%

MSCI, Associate

Feb 2018 – May 2022 (3.3 Years)

Projects: Alcyone Data Manager

Contributions:

- 1. Developed financial rations calculation components
- 2. Generated and deployed large volume of historical data with data correction UI and Utilities
- 3. Replaced JavaScript code by java to improve runtime performance by 20%
- 4. Automated script generation, deployment and rollback tool to speedup environment setup
- 5. Prototyped web-based tool with json configured UI generation for on demand computation

CitiusTech Healthcare Technology, SSE

Jun 2014 - Feb 2018 (3.8 Years)

Projects: BIC Rule Engine

Contributions:

- 1. Worked on code module for text-based rule parser and executor
- 2. Developed error reporting tool using JavaFX and Apache POI

Education

Master's in computer applications (MCA)

Apr 2011 - Jun 2014

Sardar Patel Institute of Technology, University of Mumbai

Bachelor of Science, Mathematics (B.Sc.)

Apr 2007 – Mar 2011

Ramniranjan Jhunjhunwala College, University of Mumbai